Michael Chimezie

Frontend Engineer

Solution-driven Front-end developer is adept at contributing to the highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, SCC, PHP, and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over **3+** years, meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations, and databases.

Address Lagos, Nigeria.

Phone (+234)8127804055

E-mail chimzeboi07@gmail.com

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-chimezie-43680a1bb/

Github https://github.com/Michael-ael
Twitter https://twitter.com/michael_ael
Website https://michael-web.netlify.app/

Education

University of Nigeria, Nsukka

B.Sc Computer Science SEPT 2017 - 2022 Completing 8 semesters towards a degree in computer science.

Skills

Software Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Jquery, PHP, GSAP, UI improvement, Figma

Personal

Team spirit, Critical thinking, Problem-solving.

Others

Open-source contributor, Community leader, Developer mentor.

Experience

Varscon Ltd. June 2021 - Present

React.is Engineer

Varscon comprises an eclectic team of professional engineers that handle the **research**, **product design**, and development cycle of **business technology** so that entrepreneurs can focus on business logic and management of their idea while the team at Varscon does the heavy lifting.

On the Varscon team

- I maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies, including styled components and redux.
- Validated customer interface requirements and assessed the impact of needs on available systems.
- Created mobile applications based on React, integrating Facebook's best practices for interface design.

https://varscongroup.com

Upwork February 2019 - present. Frontend Developer (Freelancer)

- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quick-loading sites with particular layouts.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Consulted with customers to gather requirements and discuss design choices.

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01327f728e834b520b

Interest

Programming, Music, Travelling, Entrepreneurship, Business.

Thoughts

TLDR; I am awesome and you really should hire me!

In my career as a software developer, I have explored many software sectors. Frontend Development, Backend Development, Automation Tools, UI/UX design, etc. I have been able to amass a huge amount of knowledge over the years just for one singular reason, I love adventure. I am passionate about learning new stuff. Something about that is extremely intriguing to me and even though half of the time I don't catch on to the concepts on the first trial, it's always a breeze the next time. It is refreshing to know that I am able to apply my tenacity to software projects I work on and bring a new wind of innovation to what I am working on. Also, my flexibility when it comes to technologies is out of this world. I don't see the syntax, I see patterns and it helps me be able to work out any logic in any framework or the language of choice. You should know that I don't think there is a "perfect" technology stack. I study the systems and see the flaws and the benefits and I decide if they are necessary evils for the particular use case.